Guide to the Pennsylvania Peace Links Records, 1978-2007 AIS.2004.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Soviet Women's Visits, 1985-1994; VIII.
  - PR & Events One Ballet, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Press Releases, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Tribute Dinner, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Chautauqua/Pitt Conference, October-November 1989 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Clippings - PL/Chautauqua at Pitt, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Falk, Loti, 1986-1988 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Internships, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Margie, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Nash, Graham, et al, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Paradise, Mary – USSR visit, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Pittsburgh Music Society, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Russian Women Visit, April-May 1992 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Soviet Women, April-May 1992 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Russian Visitors, April-May 1992 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Press Releases, April-May 1992 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Scott, Pam & OUCS, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Tereshenko, Lyudmilla, Maryland, August 1994 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Artwork from Russian Children, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Children's Art Exhibit, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Soviet Women's Committee, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Soviet Women's Visit People Lists, October 19-22, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Soviet Women's Exchange Pittsburgh/Ligonier Itinerary, October 19-22, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Soviet Women's Trip, October, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 39-40)
  - Soviet Women's Trip National Exchanges, 1987-1989 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - PL/Soviet Trip, October, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Evaluations of Soviet Women's Visit, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Scrapbook, 1985-1987 (Box 15, Folder 44-45)
  - Telex, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Thursday Review, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - USIA, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - USSR Ad hoc Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - USSR Exchange, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - US-USSR Exchanges – Avant-garde Foundation, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - New Material Added, 2011
    - "Russians Are Coming", 1985 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Pitt-Chautauqua - Soviet Visitors, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Soviet Correspondence of Peace Links Events, 1984-1988 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Soviets, Meet Middle America, 1987-1988 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Soviet Women's Visit, 1985-1989 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - US-USSR Exchange, 1987-1988 (Box 22, Folder 29)
- Photographs, 1983-2003; IX.
  Series includes photographs that have been identified, when possible, by the Peace Links Board members as representations of a particular meeting, annual dinner, or special event. The main events represented here are annual dinners, visits by Russians, and Chautauqua trips. Additional photographs are interspersed throughout the collection. New materials were added June 2011 in the section entitled, "New Material Added, 2011".
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, 1983-2003 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Annual Dinners, 1990-2001 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Pitt Informal Programs, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Harrisburg Peace Garden, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Russian Leadership Program, September, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Russian's Visit, September, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Chautauqua, 1997-2002 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Early Childhood Institute, Carlow College Program and Puppet Show, April, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Chinese Delegation/CPAPD, 1991-2003 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Peace Links 14th and 18th Annual Dinners, 1997, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Peace Links 19th Annual Dinner, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Russian Leaders visit to Pittsburgh, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Various Photographs, 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Slides-House Painting/Fred Rogers, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Photos for press, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - New Material Added, 2011
    - Ekaterina Shevelova Event, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Harrisburg Peace Garden, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 31)
- Audio-Visual Material, 1980-2000; X.
  This series was originally part of the Aaron Levinson Audio-Visual library, named for a local philanthropist who participated enthusiastically in fundraising efforts on behalf of Peace Links. Some of the films were given or purchased by Peace Links, some were also taped from television. Inventories of the Levinson Library at various stages of its existence are in Series II. New materials were added June 2011 in the section entitled, "New Material Added, 2011".
  - Films, 1980-2000; 1.
    - "Back from the Brink: End the Nuclear Threat Now", undated (Box 17, Cassette 1)
    - "Breaking the Spell", undated (Box 17, Cassette 2)
    - "Building Bombs", undated (Box 17, Cassette 3)
    - "Children and the Nuclear War", undated (Box 17, Cassette 4)
    - "Children of War Tour", 1984 (Box 17, Cassette 5)
    - "Guns for Guatemala", undated (Box 17, Cassette 6)
    - "Health, Wealth, and National Security: Colorado Coalition for the Prevention of Nuclear War", undated (Box 17, Cassette 7)
    - "In the Nuclear Shadow" (2 copies), undated (Box 17, Cassette 8-9)
    - "International Physicians for Social Responsibility"/"What Soviet Children are Saying about Nuclear War", undated (Box 17, Cassette 10)
    - "Jordan's Stormy Banks", 1991 (Box 17, Cassette 11)
    - "Lanterns for Hope", undated (Box 17, Cassette 12)
    - "Letters From A Dead Man"/"Breaking the Spell", undated (Box 17, Cassette 13)
    - "Mylar", with Rick Santorum, undated (Box 17, Cassette 14)
    - "NOVA Frontline: Strategic Defense Initiative", undated (Box 17, Cassette 15)
    - "NOVA: The Bomb's Lethal Legacy", undated (Box 17, Cassette 16)
    - "Nowhere to Hide", with Ramsey Clark, undated (Box 17, Cassette 17)
    - "Peace Links", undated (Box 17, Cassette 18)
    - "Preventing Nuclear War: The First Essential Step", undated (Box 17, Cassette 19)
    - "Preventing the Final Mistake", undated (Box 17, Cassette 20)
    - "Russian Leadership Program", 2000 (Box 17, Cassette 21)
    - "Soviet Children Reaction to Nuclear Weapons", undated (Box 17, Cassette 22)
    - "Stopping War Before It Starts", undated (Box 17, Cassette 23)
    - "The Art of Being Human" (2 copies), undated (Box 17, Cassette 24-25)
    - "The Edge of History" (7 copies), undated (Box 17, Cassette 26-32)
    - "The Missiles/Rehearsing Doomsday", undated (Box 17, Cassette 33)
    - "The Tree House", undated (Box 17, Cassette 34)
    - "War Toys Conference" (2 copies), undated (Box 17, Cassette 35-36)
    - "What About the Children?", undated (Box 17, Cassette 37)
    - "Back From the Brink: End the Nuclear Threat Now" (2 copies), undated (Box 17, Cassette 1-2)
    - "Betty Linden Interview", 1986 (Box 17, Cassette 3)
    - "Beyond War: An Introductory Presentation", undated (Box 17, Cassette 4)
    - "Century of Non-Violence", undated (Box 17, Cassette 6)
    - "Century of Non-Violence II", undated (Box 17, Cassette 5)
    - "Do Kirk Workshop", undated (Box 17, Cassette 7)
    - "Dr. Lown-Peace Links Dinner ", (2 copies), 1990 (Box 17, Cassette 8-9)
    - "Drops of Water, Grains of Sand", undated (Box 17, Cassette 10)
    - "Fail Safe", undated (Box 17, Cassette 11)
    - "Focus On: Lee Hicks", undated (Box 17, Cassette 12)
    - "In Search of Glasnost and Perestroika", undated (Box 17, Cassette 13)
    - "Interview on China with Carl Goldstein", 1993 (2 copies) (Box 17, Cassette 14-15)
    - "Interview with Carl Goldstein", undated (Box 17, Cassette 16)
    - "Let Us Begin: What Are We Making Weapons For?", 1986 (Box 17, Cassette 17)
    - "Making Things Happen: Spreading the Vote", undated (Box 17, Cassette 18)
    - "No Grapes", undated (Box 17, Cassette 19)
    - "Nuclear Bomb Factories", undated (Box 17, Cassette 20)
    - "Paving the Way for a Peaceful Future", undated (Box 17, Cassette 21)
    - "Peace Links 11th Annual Dinner", 1994 (Box 17, Cassette 22)
    - "Peace Links 9th Annual Dinner", 1992 (Box 17, Cassette 23)
    - "Peace Links Press Conference", 1980 (Box 17, Cassette 24)
    - "Peace Links Workshop-Conflict Resolution", undated (Box 17, Cassette 25)
    - "Peace Train to Beijing: A Project of the Women's International League for Peace and Freedom", undated (Box 17, Cassette 26)
    - "Phil Donahue in Russia", undated (Box 17, Cassette 27)
    - "Press Conference and Peace Link Luncheon-Heinz Hall", 1983 (Box 17, Cassette 28)
    - "Report on the United Nations 4th World Conference for Women" (Box 17, Cassette 29)
    - "Soviet Women Visit" (2 copies), 1985 (Box 17, Cassette 30-31)
    - "Sticks and Stones: A Modern Fable", undated (Box 17, Cassette 32)
    - "The Common Ground Approach to Conflict Resolution", undated (Box 17, Cassette 33)
    - "The Military and the Environment", undated (Box 17, Cassette 34)
    - "The Shadow of Hate: A History of Intolerance in America", undated (Box 17, Cassette 35)
    - "US/USSR Youth Exchange Program", undated (Box 17, Cassette 36)
    - "Vladimir Pozner – Peace Links Dinner", 1992 (Box 17, Cassette 37)
    - "What About the Russians?", undated (Box 17, Cassette 38)
    - "Women for America for the World" (2 copies), undated (Box 17, Cassette 39-40)
    - Unlabeled: Interview with Margaret Taux (?) and final 3 installments of "Peter Ustinov's Russia", undated (Box 17, Cassette 41)
    - "Anti-Contra Aid Ad"- 2-inch reel-to-reel, 1986 (Box 19, Reel 1)
    - "Arkansas Peace Links Panel January 27, 1983" - Audio Cassette (Box 19, Cassette 1)
  - VHS, undated; 2.
    - "Harrisburg Peace Garden", undated (Box 19, Cassette 2)
    - "Star Wars Defense: Can It Work?", undated (Box 19, Cassette 3)
  - U-Matic, 1984-1988; 3.
    - "Building Bridges of Trust", Undated (Box 19, Cassette 4)
    - "Edge of History", undated (Box 19, Cassette 5)
    - "PL/Pt. Park College - SDI" Edited, undated (Box 19, Cassette 6)
    - "PL/Pt. Park College - SDI" Unedited, undated (Box 19, Cassette 7)
    - "Preventing Nuclear War: The First Essential Step", 1985 (Box 19, Cassette 8)
    - "Reception for Soviet Women", 1985 (Box 19, Cassette 9)
    - "The Last Epidemic: The Medical Consequences of Nuclear Weapons and Nuclear War", undated (Box 19, Cassette 10)
    - "Through the Arts: Cultural Exchange for Peace, Interview", 1988 (Box 19, Cassette 11)
    - "Weapons in Space" Union of Concerned Scientists, 1984 (Box 19, Cassette 12)
    - "What About the Children", May 1984 (Box 19, Cassette 13)
    - "Women for America", undated (Box 19, Cassette 14)
  - Beta, 1986; 4.
    - "It's up to the Women", undated (Box 19, Cassette 15)
    - "Paul Warnke-SDI", 1986 (Box 19, Cassette 16)
    - "Space Weapons: An Overview", undated (Box 19, Cassette 17)
    - "Teresa Wilson on Soviet Women", undated (Box 19, Cassette 18)
    - "The Challenge of the Caucuses and Breaking the Spell", undated (Box 19, Cassette 19)
    - "The Power of the Atom with Peter Jennings", undated (Box 19, Cassette 20)
  - 16mm film, undated; 5.
    - "A Call to Peace", undated (Box 20, Reel 1)
    - "If You Lose this Planet", undated (Box 20, Reel 2)
    - "In the Nuclear Shadow", undated (Box 20, Reel 3)
    - "The Last Epidemic", undated (Box 20, Reel 4)
    - "War Without Winners II", undated (Box 20, Reel 5)
    - "What About the Russians", undated (Box 20, Reel 6)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 20, Reel 7)
    - "The Edge of History", undated (Box 21, Reel 8)
    - "Women for America, For the World" (2 copies), undated (Box 21, Reel 9-10)
  - New Material Added, 2011
    - "Drops of Water, Grains of Sand", undated (Box 23, Cassette 1)
    - Freeport Riverside Park, August, 5, 1989 (Box 23, Cassette 2)
    - Harrisburg Peace Garden, undated (Box 23, Cassette 3)
    - International Peace Lantern Exchange Project, 1985-1988 (Box 23, Cassette 4)
    - Katerina Shevelova Television Interview, April 13, 1988 (Box 24, Cassette 1)
    - Lantern CER, 1988 (Box 24, Cassette 2)
    - Lanterns for Hope, International Peace Exchange, Tape 6 of 6, undated (Box 24, Cassette 3)
    - Peace Links, Side 1, undated (Box 24, Cassette 4)
    - Peace Garden of Riverfront Park - Harrisburg, Pa., undated (Box 24, Cassette 5)
- Related Organizations, 1983-1999; XI.
  This series includes detailed files on Peace Link's correspondence and involvement with other local and national organizations devoted to peace and nuclear arm control. Files include notes, pamphlets, brochures, newsletters, and letters. Among the most detailed files include Peace Link's involvement with the formation of the high school group, Youth Cry and their correspondence with the Committee for National Security. The complete series was added to the collection in June of 2011 after a 2009 donation from Dr. Jack Paradise.
  - Alle-Kiski Valley Citizens for Peace, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - American Association of University Women, 1983-1987 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Business Executives for Nuclear Arms Control, 1983 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Pittsburgh Children's Festival, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Center for Defense Information, 1985-1990 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Pittsburgh Coalition to Prevent Nuclear War, 1985-1989 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Committee for National Security, 1985-1987 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Council for a Livable World, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Federal Emergency Management Agency, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Friends of Frick Fine Arts, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Gray Panthers, 1983-1988 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - International Peace Lantern Exchange Project, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Lawyers Alliance for Nuclear Arms Control, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - League of Women Voters, 1982-1999 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - The Marketing Place, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Musicians Against Nuclear Arms, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - National Council of Jewish Women, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - National Organization of Women (NOW), 1986-1987 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - National Peace Academy, 1982-1983 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Office of Urban and Community Services (OUCS), 1983-1984 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Pro-Peace, 1985-1986 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Peace Institute, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Pittsburgh Council for International Visitors (PCIV), 1985 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - Performing Artists for Nuclear Disarmament, undated (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Shadyside Study Group, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Smith, Jane Samantha Foundation, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Student/Teacher Organization to Prevent (STOP) Nuclear War, 1981-1983 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Thomas Merton Center, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - United Nations, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - UNITED Nations Association of Pittsburgh, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - Women's Action for Nuclear Disarmament (WAND); Caldicott, Helen, 1983-1990 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - Women's Legislative Exchange, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - Women for a Meaningful Summit, July 17-19, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Women for Racial and Economic Equality (WREE), 1991 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - World Federalists, 1983-1992 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - YMCA, 1984-1988 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - YMCA Pioneer Club, 1986-1988 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - Youth Cry, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - YWCA, 1983-1988 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - ZONTA, 1985-1987 (Box 25, Folder 40)